www  .  OpenSubtitles  .  org
Osman is out of his mind.
Does he think he can beat us
with a handful of men?
Treacherous dog!
Archers!
2 DAYS AGO
Little lamb.
Little lamb. You are sweeter
than honey. Little lamb.
Look. brother wolf is also here.
Come. brother wolf.
My comrade brother
who likes the fog.
Brother who guides us
on our journeys.
My dear ones. The secret
has been revealed.
The secret has been revealed.
By the crescent. The secret
has been revealed.
He read. The Orphan
of Makkah read.
Make way. He is coming.
The beautiful-named. handsome
Muhammad (pbuh) is coming.
Cover me. cover me.
cover your beloved.
He read. The Orphan
of Makkah read.
He read. Chosroes was shaken.
He read and the Zoroastrian's
fire was extinguished.
He read and oppression ended.
the world was enlightened.
The chosen one is coming.
There are paths. which make the
hearts strong and the minds sharp.
My heart has matured
and my mind is sharp.
You were non-existent.
you came to existence.
You were existent.
you became non-existent.
Neither existence or non-existence...
The main thing is unity.
Unity is the great state.
Hu to the one who
has the state.
becomes the state.
Hu!
This door is
the door of the state.
the door of the soldier.
A soldier needs an unbreakable
wrist. mind and courage.
Leaders. pious ones. scholars
who became one for Allah's sake.
greetings to you!
Long live our state.
May the world be enlightened.
May the marching warrior become
the state of the world.
May he become the state.
Welcome.
Thank you.
Please. take a seat.
Sweet Little lamb.
Allah created man.
gave him intellect and a soul.
The beauty of the mind is the tongue.
The beauty of the tongue is speech.
I have heard and it's the reality.
Everything that came to exist
from nothing will cease to exist.
What we call life will pass
like a wind.
I have heard and it's the reality.
But. if one holds both worlds
in balance. he will find peace.
A Bey will be blessed
if he follows the tradition.
When Almighty Allah bestows
a blessing on a Bey.
then he himself. his state and
his people are blessed.
I have heard and it's the reality.
Now it's time to unlock your heart
and sharpen your mind.
I was invited.
and I came to the White-Beard council.
My mission is to rekindle
the fire of our hearth.
We know your mission
and we know you.
But. do you know yourself?
I apologise if I made a mistake.
Those who understand will understand
and those who know will know.
He who knows and understands
will fulfil his mission.
From now on. the sword you wear.
the horse you ride. the bed you sleep on.
the path you tread and the
dream you have aren't yours.
The time is not yours.
the place is not yours.
The children are not yours.
your breath is not yours!
Whose are they?
They belong to the people.
The people. your people!
The world is on fire.
devastated and is being destroyed.
The army of the devil
is attacking and killing.
People expect hope from us.
they want us to fight.
How will we achieve that?
By being a Turk and remaining a Muslim.
And not everyone can do it.
but an honourable man.
From our forefather. Oğuz to Saltuk Buğra Han.
and from Saltuk Buğra Han to Alp Arslan.
and many more great People.
I salute them all.
And may all our salutations reach the
Sultan of the worlds. Muhammad (pbuh)
and his companions.
Peace be upon him.
Osman. son of Ertuğrul.
The army of the devil
is laying waste to the world.
and the army of the Turks
bring peace and order.
We'll establish such a state that
wolf and sheep will co-exist.
We'll establish a state that
hides no lies and secrets.
will be everlasting.
May my blood and life
be sacrificed for this state.
May my mind and heart
Our legend begins now. you came
and we became acquainted.
And we shared our thoughts.
Our first mission is to make
our people dream of a state.
This is such a dream that 72 nations.
the 7 continents and the 4 directions
will join under this dream.
It is such a dream that
everyone will find peace.
DOMANIÇ PLATEAU
We spent this summer in Domaniç.
Time is passing quickly. Thanks to Allah.
our animals have fattened well.
Our women gathered all the crops
and prepared the winter supplies.
Who is this?
Is it you. Yusuf?
I'm in a dark well.
Hasan. it's you?
Who is this?
Whose hands are these?
These hands. these iron holding hands
are the hands of my little blacksmith. Ahmet.
Bless these flower-picking hands.
My brave Ahmet. Gonca Hatun.
give Ahmet your treats.
Here you go.
Have you prepared your load?
I helped my father but our work isn't done.
There is a lot of work left.
We can only move after
the caravan leaves.
Why is that?
My father said. if my mother was here.
things would be done a lot quicker.
What are we here for. my Ahmet?
Of course we'll help you.
Gonca. you can go with him.
I will come after I finish here.
Come on. Ahmet. Let's go.
Shall we race? Who is going to win?
Let's do it.
Children smell like heaven. my Bala.
Ahmet is an orphan. my heart aches
every time I look at him.
It's because your soft heart
wants to be a mother.
It's been a long time since you
married Osman Bey. my daughter.
It's time for you to have your own
children already. time is going.
And. Osman is the son of a Bey.
He can't be without a child.
especially without soldiers.
Allah is the one who gives
and takes. Hazal Hatun.
Of course...
but...
you should try too.
If not. find a solution.
Look. people are talking. They say
Bala Hatun will not have a baby.
Eventually. they'll get into
Osman's head too. They're men.
They're impatient.
Before you know it. you'll be sharing
your tent with another woman.
If it's in my destiny. I'll live with it.
I'm like your mother. If you
have a problem. tell me.
It's also my responsibility
to find a solution.
Let's take this caravan to Söğüt first.
we'll talk plenty later.
If God permits.
MashaAllah my lion. MashaAllah!
Where are you going so hurriedly. Ahmet Alp?
Boran Alp. let me go.
we need to go to my father.
I'll help you then. let's go.
Gonca Hatun will help us. thank you anyway.
As long as Alps do their duty. it's enough.
Eyvallah. Ahmet Alp. Eyvallah.
Come here.
Come on. my lion. Go ahead.
My Bey will get here before
we emigrate. right brother?
He will. InshaAllah.
InshaAllah.
Father. Father.
May your father die for you!
I brought you Gonca Hatun
so we can prepare faster.
- Thank you. sister.
- It's nothing. Brother Hasan.
Come on. let's get to work.
- Raid!
Come on! Take the spears.
Don't leave anyone alive! Attack!
Ahmet.
Hand over your weapons.
I entrust them to you.
This year's onions are bitter. Uncle.
Would there be fruitfulness where
the Mongols walk. nephew?
InshaAllah. when these jackals leave
our land. the onions will be like before.
I have 50 Frank soldiers.
and that many Nökers. who escaped
Geyhatu's wrath. under my command.
Just like me. they're looking
for Beys to rent their swords to.
Why would we hire people like you. Cerkutay?
I heard that you conquered Kulucahisar.
Byzantines want their revenge.
Geyhatu is also looking for
a chance to make you pay.
You need warriors like us.
Before we rent our swords to your enemies.
I came to you first.
for old times' sake.
I'm making my first offer to you.
Ahmet. Ahmet!
Father! Father!
Father. Father!
Come here. don't run!
Bala Hatun!
Ahmet.
Let go!
Let go! Bala Hatun!
We want nothing from bandits who
betray their own army and run away
when they see an alarming situation.
No problem. I made my offer. I will not insist.
My Bey. my Bey!
What is it. Saltuk? What happened?
Tekfur Alexis attacked the tribe.
women and children.
We lost many. my Bey!
What are you saying. Saltuk?
Where are Hazal and Bala Hatun?
The soldier who brought the news
said he did not know.
So the world wants to come at us.
Let them come.
And get this lot out of Söğüt.
If I see them again...
Let's go.
Help the injured.
Water for the sake of Allah!
Come on.
In the name of Allah.
INEGÖL CASTLE
- Ahmet. Ahmet! My Ahmet.
- Ahmet Alp. Ahmet Alp!
A brave man doesn't give up.
An Alp doesn't lose hope.
Osman Bey will save us all. my lion.
He'll save us.
I am an Alp of Osman Bey.
How could I bow to these cursed people. Boran Alp?
- MashaAllah. my lion.
- Move! Get up!
We are the Alps of Osman Bey.
- We are the Alps of Osman Bey.
- Move!
Father! Father!
Hey!
Inegöl's long- suffering
and enduring folk.
you couldn't sleep for a long time.
You waited in fear for a long time.
You were devastated to hear
what happened in Kulucahisar.
That cruel Osman and his men
burned our brothers alive.
They killed the babies in their mother's womb.
As if that wasn't enough.
they burned our churches!
Every place these barbarians set foot
turned into a bloodbath!
I. Alexis. Tekfur of Inegöl.
brought you peace from today on.
I took such revenge on these barbarians
that they will not forget it until they die.
We made them suffer
the same pain we suffered!
Lying degenerate!
Where is Osman?
We want to drink wine from Osman's skull.
Allah is the greatest.
I promise you. this barbarian's head
will brighten up our spears.
I promise you. all the castles
these devils conquered will be ours again.
Take them to the tent. not here.
- What's going on. Göktuğ?
- My Bey.
We were attacked in the Domaniç Plateau.
What are you talking about?
Who did this?
Inegöl Tekfur. Alexis.
What are our losses?
A lot. my Bey.
Come on. come on!
Where was my uncle then?
Where was Gündüz Bey?
What were the soldiers doing?
What were they doing?
- Hold on. brothers. Hold on.
- Eyvallah. my Bey.
- We'll overcome this too. InshaAllah.
- Hold on. brother. Hold on.
My Bey.
Speak!
Bala Hatun.
- What happened?
- Bala Hatun is injured. my Bey.
Bala.
Bala! Bala!
Mother. my heart is on fire.
Tell me she's okay.
Thanks to Allah. our girl is in good health.
Bala.
Osman.
Bala. my love.
My heart.
- Osman.
- I'm here.
Ahmet.
- Ahmet.
- What happened to Ahmet?
They captured him.
And Boran was captured.
Ahmet doesn't have a mother. Osman.
Don't leave him alone.
Save him from that hell.
Don't you worry.
With the will of Allah.
I will make their lives unbearable.
Rest now.
Rest so that when Ahmet returns.
he sees that you are healthy.
My Bala.
Move!
While they slaughtered everyone.
why did they bring us here?
They want to use us. dead or alive.
Brother.
Do not resist them!
Stand tall. but do not resist.
Think of your son.
We will get Ahmet out of here.
Come on.
Ahmet. stand behind us. my lion.
My lion. come on.
Remember. we won't resist them.
I wanted to see you in this rat hole.
So you are the closest Alps of Osman.
We are like his blood. Evelallah!
Were you with him...
- in Kulucahisar?
- Thank God...
we were destined to be
the veterans in that battle.
Osman.
Where is Osman?
He must be sharpening his dagger
to rip your heart out.
Father?
Father. get up. Father!
Come on. Father.
Come on. Father. Father.
Come on. Father!
Father.
Ahmet!
Get up. Father! Come on. Father!
Come on.
Die!
Let me go!
Let's go.
I will give these two as gifts
to Osman for Kulucahisar.
Father.
No family is without a martyr.
They even killed the pregnant
wife of Ilyas Çavuş.
How did we fall into
such a trap. uncle? How?
This is not the time to grieve
over our defeat. brother.
Osman is right. nephew.
Pull yourself together.
It's time to flare up the fire of revenge.
You are right. uncle. but when? How?
Tomorrow. Eye for an eye.
tooth for tooth.
Does our tribe have the strength. Osman?
Are our men or women powerful enough?
- Let's wait and think about it. nephew.
- Think about what. uncle?
If we don't act now.
we'll never regain our strength again.
We'll consciously be sending
the tribe towards death. Osman.
Let's take a breath.
regain our strength and power.
So that our soldiers can heal
and we regain strength. my nephew.
If you were so smart. you should have
taken action and stopped it.
If we have a weakness. they do too.
They hit us hard after so long with a raid.
Now they're drunk with victory.
Osman must be thinking that
we are drunk with victory now.
We are.
From now on.
no one will take even a sip.
Everyone will forget the Kayı tribe raid.
and remember the cruelty in Kulucahisar.
Those who forget our slaughtered children.
our destroyed sacred ornaments.
may they burn in hell.
May they be friends of the demons of hell.
What are you thinking?
We'll attack them before
they have the chance to recover.
If we give them a break.
we'll be feeding our own monsters.
We will face them tomorrow.
It'll be such a great battle that
all our saints will leave their graves
and join our army.
Jesus will descend from the heavens
and command our army.
He must have reinforced his army
with troops from Constantinople.
No doubt.
True. but...
every army has a weakness.
His army must have rested.
And their morale is strengthened.
True. it will shake us deeply.
But. their morale will be their biggest problem.
Osman. most of our Alps are exhausted.
We will strengthen their souls
and we'll heal their wounds.
- Peace be upon you.
- And peace be upon you.
How's the situation. Davut Usta?
I'm aware. the Alps aren't well.
They are injured.
And they took many of our weapons.
How many weapons
can you make by morning?
If you're going to take revenge on the enemy.
I will make weapons of any steel I see. Osman Bey.
As long as we take our revenge soon.
We shouldn't be defeated taking our revenge.
Revenge is a dish
best eaten cold. my nephew.
Even if not today.
it's day will surely come.
Strike the iron while it's hot. Dündar Bey.
We will strike them quickly
so that their victory doesn't last.
We should take their lives soon so that
our defeat doesn't become our fear.
We need to strike the down fast
so that we can bury our pain.
Forge such weapons that our victory
is told for ages to come.
With pleasure. my Bey.
How are your wounds. brother?
Not as deep as those in my heart.
Now listen to me carefully.
Eyvallah.
Osman is telling the truth.
but if we lose. we'll have to go back.
All these efforts. all this struggle.
everything will go to waste.
If only we had sent news to
my brother Yavlak Arslan.
He would come to aid with his veterans.
We have so many broken Alps.
I hope this battle won't be our disaster.
Don't worry. Hatun. Tomorrow. such a storm
will break out on these pagans that
my Lord who never abandoned
His brave soldiers in the Battle of Badr
will send the angels to help us.
Hey MashaAllah!
Let's start the preparations. then.
If you don't build a castle
from their skulls tomorrow.
I will die in disappointment.
May you live long. Hatun.
You brought back honour to my tent.
May you live long.
Tomorrow will be a good day.
INEGÖL CASTLE
Osman has a death wish.
He invites our Tekfur to a battle.
Osman will die!
Guards!
Allah is the Ever-Living!
Allah is the Everlasting Truth!
I tied your armor so tightly.
I knitted it so strong that
the weapons of the pagans
will not pass through it.
I tied your steel loop by loop. my Bey.
to shield the blood-seeking spears.
For every drop of blood they spilled.
for every life they have taken.
and for Ahmet...
I will make their life unbearable.
My Alps! If we fall. the nation falls!
If we get tired. the state will collapse!
If we win. the enemy will tremble!
My Alps!
For Allah's sake. who makes
many from the few.
who gives us courage.
and pleases our hearts.
Today.
to be exhausted.
to get tired or lose hope
are all forbidden!
Today is the Day of the Holy War.
Come on.
Ya Allah!
Allah is the greatest.
Ahmet Alp. Ahmet Alp.
Can you see? Look. Didn't I tell you
Osman Bey would come?
Osman is out of his mind.
Does he think he can beat us
with a handful of men?
Osman Bey!
Treacherous dog!
Do not stand still. brothers.
Move left and right. come on!
Archers!
Göktuğ. go on!
Die. Osman!
Attack!
Protect Ahmet!
Let's go. my lions!
Allah is the greatest.
What are we going to do?
Attack!
When do you think the news
will come. Davut Usta?
How would I know. man?
I hope good news will come.
People expect hope from us.
They want us to fight.
How will we achieve that?
By being a Turk and remaining a Muslim.
May my blood and life
be sacrificed for this state.
No one touches the prisoners.
Take care of the injured.
They didn't treat us like that. my Bey.
They made us vomit blood.
We should be different.
We should be different so that
our merciful Prophet (pbuh)
becomes proud of us.
Eyvallah. my Bey. Eyvallah.
All praise and glory
be for You. my Lord.
Praise and glory be to You.
My dear Lord.
You gave us strength.
You gave us courage.
We were helpless.
You made us strong.
We were few.
You made us many.
Oh my Lord. protect us
from arrogance!
Aameen!
Protect us from arrogance.
Protect us from arrogance!
Aameen!
My dear Lord! Praise be to You.
- Praise be to You!
May this army. this nation
be sacrificed for You!
- Sacrificed for You!
Accept our prayers!
Aameen!
- Accept our prayers!
- Aameen!
- Accept our prayers. my Lord.
Justice forever. freedom forever!
- Allah is the Greatest!
CONSTANTINOPLE
You are the only artist
I take inspiration from.
My only struggle is to protect
the legacy you left behind.
I am absolutely sure that
I will achieve this.
You are the greatest example of
how difficult it is to become an artist.
I admire your ability
of overcoming challenges.
You never gave up. Never.
Great and mighty Caesar! Your greatest
monument is the Roman Empire.
You created it by shedding
the blood of the enemy.
forgiving no traitor and by
breathing courage into cowards.
However. great Caesar!
Rome is fighting for its life today.
The Roman Empire is under
the attack of the Barbarians.
However. Pompeos. Spartacuses and
Brutuses continue to gnaw at Rome.
I. Aya Nikola. promise you.
I will rebuild the great and
mighty Roman Empire.
Salute the mighty Caesar. soldier!
My magic fingers have recreated Caesar.
Flawless.
The emperor is waiting for you.
Mighty Caesar.
Finally.
Alexis. Tekfur of Inegöl.
as if being defeated by the Kayıs
wasn't bad enough.
ran away from the battle
like a rat and hid in his castle.
How could he do that?
How dare he?
What next after the Karacahisar
and Kulucahisar castles?
Iznik? Bursa?
Or Constantinople?
Enough!
Just as we got rid of
the Crusader's army.
it's time to get rid of the Turks as well.
There's only one commander in
our empire I believe can do that.
I invited him to the Council.
Emperor.
Distinguished members of the Council.
You know why you're here.
Because you are sick and tired
of cowardice and betrayal.
To put an end to the
harassment of the enemies.
You invited me to unite the east
of our Empire with my iron fist.
However!
However. I have two conditions.
If you allow me.
I will take back Kulucahishar
that Osman Bey conquered.
I will also take back Karacahisar
that his father conquered.
But this will not eliminate
the threat of the Turks to our Empire.
You will applaud me. drown me
in gold and promote me.
But this little gift I will
give to you will not stop
us from melting like snow
on a mountain peak in the sun.
Then. what is your offer. Nikola?
I want full command of all the soldiers.
Tekfurs and border patrol units in the area.
Full authority.
Not to take back the castles we lost.
to take back everything.
to take back everything we lost.
Our lands. churches. villages. bridges.
to take back the honour we lost.
Long story short.
I want full and unquestioned authority from you.
for the souls we have lost.
Emperor.
What about your second condition?
I will gather my own men.
and the leader of this group
will be your biggest enemy. Flatyos.
Don't we have any food?
We're hungry.
No I can't do this. My heart's going to explode.
I can't wait. we need to find a solution.
What solution?
A solution to quickly inform
those waiting curiously for news.
Davut Usta! Davut Usta!
Thank you Allah.
My lions!
- MashaAllah!
- All praise be to You. Allah!
- Move. let's go.
Our Bey is here.
Make way.
Is victory ours?
Thank you Allah. Thanks to you.
Welcome. my Bey.
May Allah bless you with many
more victories. InshaAllah!
Ahmet.
How many infidels did
you cut down. my Ahmet?
May I be sacrificed for you!
Look at me.
My father became a martyr.
You are here safe and sound.
We couldn't be grateful enough.
Thank you. Gonca Hatun.
May you live long.
Praise be to Allah who
blessed us with this victory.
Aameen!
Brave Kayı folk! I will keep it short!
- Thanks to Allah. we defeated the enemy!
- Thanks to Allah.
Thanks to Allah.
Now. we must defeat ourselves!
Eyvallah.
Our friendship ends here.
Forgive me.
Constantine.
My dear friend.
Byzantine is resurrecting.
What is going on there?
What is that?
Let me introduce him to you.
Constantine.
He is escaping!
Constantine. my dear friend.
I am grateful to you.
Nikola.
How wonderful it is to
see you after so many years.
The dungeons didn't rust you.
Revenge kept me alive.
I came to give you a new mission.
On the day I escape?
Go out of my way.
You didn't stop those
who put me here?
Thank you my friend.
You saved my life.
I have completed my duty. Nikola.
If you do not have an order.
I would like to return to my business.
I knew every pain that you went through.
I knew every meal you had.
I came today.
to see if all my efforts were in vain or not.
I hope I haven't disappointed you.
But. do not forget that Flatyos
is nobody's dog.
Flatyos. I came to offer you the opportunity
to destroy Ertuğrul and the Kayıs.
Finally. God.
Finally.
INEGÖL CASTLE
1 DAY AFTER
Nikola.
The emperor heard us
and sent you.
for the love of Jesus!
Today will be our day of salvation.
Welcome.
Welcome. my old friend.
Were these with you while you were
running away from the Kayıs. Alexis?
Are you here to interrogate us
or help us. Nikola?
To call to account.
But not you.
the Kayıs.
I brought you a gift. Alexis.
I hope you like it.
Thank you. Nikola.
I hope you like the meal
I prepared for you.
Your favourite. pork stew
with artichoke. I didn't forget.
I like it.
Traitor!
Great Caesar. my first move was to
rid this castle of incompetent people.
I feel honored to present
the last one to you.
I don't like cowardice.
Kneel before the Emperor's loyal
new Tekfur of Inegöl. Aya Nikola.
Now it's time to clear the
enemies outside the castle.
Shortly. with my will and the spirit of Helen.
a brand new Rome will rise!
May Jesus bless you. Tekfur Nikola.
May he bless us all. Pope.
all of us.
Bala.
What are you doing?
How can you prepare when I'm here?
Come on. sit down.
It's hard for me to make you sit
at the table I didn't prepare. Osman.
And you're tired from battle.
Please don't deprive me of this honour.
My beautiful and sweet Bala.
you already gave me the greatest
honour of your presence in my heart.
Besides. I can set the table very well.
Come sit down.
Osman Bey. can I come in?
Come in.
What is it?
There's news from Ertuğrul Bey.
Dündar Bey invites you to his tent.
Osman.
May it be good. Osman.
He'll be here soon.
Bring the clothes.
There's news about my father. uncle.
Kuzgun Bey from the Çobanoğullar.
messenger of Yavlak Arslan.
- Welcome. Kuzgun Bey.
- I have news from Ertuğrul Bey.
May Allah bless you for bringing
good news from my father.
Eyvallah. Osman Bey.
Yavlak Arslan and Ertuğrul Bey will meet in
Kastamonu and discuss the Byzantine threats.
- Ertuğrul Bey is waiting in Badembükü.
- Is my brother well?
Well enough to spoil
the plans of the infidels.
MashaAllah.
Then let's set off right away.
Ertuğrul Bey wants Osman alone.
That's the order I was given.
Yavlak Arslan also wants to see Osman Bey
who fought bravely in Kulucahisar and the battlefield.
Ertuğrul Bey wants you to set off at dawn.
You brought us happiness. Kuzgun Bey.
You made us happy.
Eyvallah. I've done my duty.
I brought the news.
I'll be on my way now.
Do you know the Rubicon River. Flatyos?
The river Julius Caesar crossed
with his legions
to become emperor by conquering Rome.
Not an emperor. rather a god.
He was declared a God by the consul.
And my Rubicon River
flows in these lands.
The Sakarya River.
when the time comes I will cross
that river with my army.
That river. Flatyos.
will carry me to the empire of Rome.
Did I tell you that I was baptized
in the Sakarya River?
From that day. every river in
the world flows through me.
Like Julius Caesar.
It looks more like you
than Julius Caesar.
Can you see any differences between us?
I can't. What's inside this...
The great pain I'm going to unleash
on Söğüt is hidden in this little box.
First Söğüt then Karacahisar.
Tears and blood will conquer
every place the Turks conquered.
Then...
we'll start our path to victory. Flatyos.
To our victory.
Did Ertuğrul Bey's summon of only
Osman confuse you. my Bey?
Do you think he'd call me. Hazal?
Of course he would. Dündar Bey.
Aren't you the brother of Ertuğrul Gazi.
Aren't you the honorable Bey of this tribe?
May Allah give my years to my brother.
However. when he comes here.
how will I show my face.
that's what I think about.
The past is in the past. Dündar Bey.
If he was going to do anything
we'd know by now.
Also. Ertuğrul Bey's mercy is as
well known as his justice.
His justice is also know. Hatun.
I have no doubt.
but. I don't understand why Osman
goes while you are here.
If you talk about experience. you have it.
talk about bravery. you are.
Ertuğrul Gazi has wisdom
and the decree.
He knows best what to do.
Have a nice day.
Let me have a look at that.
Ertuğrul Bey.
Ertuğrul Bey is coming!
Brother.
Father.
Long live Ertuğrul Bey!
Welcome Ertuğrul Bey!
Father.
- Welcome. Father.
- Thank you.
Welcome. brother. Welcome.
I missed all of you.
Thank you. brother.
My Bey.
Where is Osman?
I didn't see Osman.
- Didn't you call Osman. my Bey?
- What are you talking about. Dündar?
Where is Osman?
Wasn't Osman with you. my Bey?
What are you talking about. Gündüz?
- What is happening here?
- My Bey...
Yavlak Arslan's messenger.
Kuzgun Bey was here yesterday.
He said you called Osman.
Nobody knew I was coming to the tribe.
The secret has been revealed.
Cain killed Able and the secret is no more.
Father Adam cried.
His tears were like a flood.
Everywhere it was flooded.
Mountains became islands.
lands became sea.
A voice was heard in the flood.
"Give me your hand."
What are you waiting for. son?
Give me your hand.
Don't upset your father.
give me your hand. son.
Look. Father Noah wants you.
give me your hand.
Would a father let his son die?
Give me your hand.
Don't upset your father. Noah.
give me your hand. son.
You'll drown. give me your hand.
He didn't give his hand.
Father Noah cried.
A teardrop fell in the sea.
The sea showed mercy and gave
Father Noah peace of mind.
Oh love. now tell me.
Who is the father?
Who is the son?
www  .  OpenSubtitles  .  org